Raskin, A. H. Papers 6029
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
A. H. Raskin Papers
1940-1985
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Raskin, A. H.
6029
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
This collection includes newspaper columns written by Raskin folded in envelopes.
5767223
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 15, 2014
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, April 29, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Abraham H. Raskin was born April 26, 1911 in Edmonton, Canada and raised in Seattle. After a brief stay in Berlin, the Raskin family settled in New York. Raskin started at the City College of New York in 1927 and studied education and government. During his time at college, he became interested in journalism and edited the student newspaper, yearbook and literary magazine. After graduation in 1931, Raskin remained for a time and took some graduate courses, and also did part-time work at "The New York Times" as a campus correspondent. In 1934, he became a full time employee at the "Times" and reported on unemployment before becoming a labor correspondent. During World War II, Raskin was chief of the Army Industrial Service Division, entering the service as a captain and being discharged with the rank of lieutenant colonel. Returning to "The New York Times," Raskin became the chief labor correspondent. He followed the strikes, disputes, and negotiations, from the coal mines, to the steel mills, and the auto factories. He was on a first name basis with union leaders and management. In 1961, Raskin joined the editorial board and later became the assistant editor of the editorial page. He spent more than four decades at "The New York Times" covering labor, writing articles, and overseeing editorials, while becoming an authority on labor and industrial relations. Raskin died in 1993 at the age of 82.
Scope and Contents
Photocopies may duplicate them completely. Series 1 - NY Times articles 1940-1970 bulk. Series 2, Research notes for articles on Dennis Rivera and 1199.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1 5680 OH: Local 1199 Oral History Project 5733: Peter Seitz Arbitration Files 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles 6036/012: Abe Raskin Collection 6046: Archives Union File (AUF) 6218 AV: Melvyn Dubofsky Audio-Visual Materials
Raskin, A. H. (Abraham Henry), 1911-1993; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees. Local 1199 Drug & Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.), Archives
5767223
- A Reporter at Large; 'A Unionist in Reaganland', 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A Reporter at Large, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Misc., 1975-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Newspaper Clippings + Memos of Abe Haskin, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- A Kind of Economic Holy War, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 'Voting for Unemployment' Gregg Easterbrook, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- A. H. Raskin, 1946-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Magazines - Fortune, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The New York Times Magazine, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Raskin Papers 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- A.H. Raskin - Long Paper (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- A.H. Raskin - Long Paper (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Industrial Relations Research Association Series - 30th Annual Meeting, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Dues - Early Draft, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Articles and Papers A.H. Raskin, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Dues Result, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Editorials, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Rivera Election - Quotes, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings + Notes, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- A.H. Raskin - Health Dissertation, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- A.H. Raskin, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Misc., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Raskin Sources, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Raskin By-Lines Jan-June 1959 B-427 479 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- -Bylines- Raskin, Abe, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- -Bylines- Jan-June 1952 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- -Bylines- Raskin 1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- -Bylines- Raskin 1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- -Bylines- Raskin 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- -By-lines- Raskin Jan-June 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- -By-Lines- Raskin July-Dec 1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- -By-Lines- Raskin July-Dec 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- -By-Lines- A.H. Raskin Jan-June 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- -By-Lines Raskin Jan-Sept. 1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- By-Lines Raskin July-Dec. 1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- -By-Lines Raskin July-Dec 1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- By-Lines Raskin 1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- By-Lines Raskin 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- -By-Lines- Talese, Gay 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1946 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- -By-Lines- Raskin 1945 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 1940+1944 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- 1945-1949 Folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- 1945-1949 Folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- 1945-1949 folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- 1950-1954 folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- 1950-1954 folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- 1950-1954 Folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- 1950-1954 Folder 4 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- 1955-1957 Folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- 1955-1957 Folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- 1955-1957 Folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- 1958-1960 Folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- 1958-1960 Folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 1958-1960 Folder 3 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- 1960-1963 Folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- 1964-1968 Folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- 1968-1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)